JAMES DOBBE

Phone: 425-457-1617 | Email: Dobbe2@gmail.com | Kirkland, WA 98034

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-dobbe/

SUMMARY

Front End Web Developer and Web Designer uses a creative approach that blends artistic and design talents with coding and development skills. Applies great people skills when collaborating with UX designers to create a visually appealing, yet functional design. Bridges the gap between graphical design and technical implementation with a feedback loop, good communication skills, and openness to new ideas and continuous learning. Creates an engaging and user friendly experience with polished, professional, and dynamic applications. A keen eye for details, creating pixel perfect responsive components.

Github: https://github.com/dobbe2/ | Portfolio: https://dobbe2.github.io/portfolio-2023/

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Strengths in: CSS, Responsive Design, Quality Assurance, and Version Control

Languages / Frameworks: ReactJS, JavaScript, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Semantic HTML5, CSS3, Node.js,

jQuery, Bootstrap

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL

Applications / Tools: Visual Studio Code, Storybook, WordPress, MySQL Workbench, Git, GitHub, Postman, Styled Components, Vector Graphics and Visual UI UX Design with Figma, Debugging Tools

EDUCATION

Web Development Bootcamp Certificate: University of Washington, Seattle, WA

Completed a 24-week intensive Full Stack Web Development program to develop programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Responsive Web Design Certificate: freeCodeCamp.org

Wordpress CMS Design Course: udemy.com Figma UI UX Design Essentials: udemy.com

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Designer, Feb 2021 – Present

Woodinville, WA

Work with businesses to design and develop websites and branding/logos. Assist in developing creative content. Keep in constant contact with clients to make sure we are always working towards the same vision.

- Designed and created a company site for a Medical Professional (https://walk-easy.vercel.app) to replace a very slow and poorly designed WordPress site.
 - Used Next.js, Tailwind CSS, and Tailwind UI Components to feature services and products offered. Collaborated with a software engineer on the code reviews.
 - o Implemented a variety of features based on stakeholder input.
 - Optimized design and assets for speed and ease of use for the client's target audience. Focused on responsive design.
- Built WordPress websites for a construction company (https://leebrannamconstruction.com) and a craft group (https://checkeredpastgals.com) to showcase projects and drive business with an elegant and modern responsive design.
 - Worked with the clients to define UX design requirements and created new brands for the businesses, including color scheme, logo, and branding verbiage. Conducted website performance tests and troubleshooting errors.

Set up the domains, hosting, and website launches. Tools: HTML, CSS, WordPress

Front End Developer, Oct 2021 – April 2022 **ZAP Protocol** Contracted through Blockchain Center, Manhattan, NY

Remotely worked with developers and designers from around the world, contributing to the redesign of a large application containing an NFT marketplace, Oracles Price Feeds, and other Exchanges. Designed with mobile development as top priority. Project can be found at https://app.zap.org/nft (requires digital wallet to view all content).

- Used design tools such as Figma and Storybook to create reusable components for the entire application and to build and test all components. A sample of component images developed can be found at https://dobbe2.github.io/zapDesignWork.
- Worked alongside design team through handoffs and bridges. Collaborated daily with front-end and design teams to keep progress pushing forward and give and receive feedback on current tasks.
- Participated in design/development meetings to gain insight into the design progress and plan for future revisions. The app used React, Typescript, styled components, and Web3.
- Received and reviewed changes to the Design System and created tickets to assign to developers.
- Converted app from a Flexbox layout to a Grid layout.
- Single handedly tasked with and completed build of the splash page for the company, www.zap.org, from Figma file to completion.
- Worked through merge conflicts in a large repository with many directories and subdirectories, and both current and old build pages.
- Performed bug testing and QA before a version release and made changes quickly and precisely.

Skills Development Project: Interactive Baseball Scoreboard 3/2021

https://github.com/dobbe2/baseballScoreboard | https://dobbe2.github.io/baseballScoreboard

Developed a visual representation of a baseball scoreboard. Programmed the many conditional situations that occur during a ball and strike count, and the runners on the basepaths. Focused on heavy game logic. Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery, RapidAPI, CSS grid

Restaurant Manager / Catering Manager / Server, Feb 2011 – October 2021 Cafe Veloce, Kirkland, WA

Always looked for perfection, providing the highest quality service possible so customers have a memorable experience. Utilize teamwork, good communications, and good time management skills, even when working under pressure. Resolve issues behind the scenes so they aren't customer facing.

- Consistently praised by customers with positive reviews and compliments.
- Voted 2nd place Best Server on the Eastside (without campaigning).